<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog EN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 12:59:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>7 Strategies to Implement When Your Website Traffic Drops</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Traffic was never an issue for you until one day &#8220;BAM!&#8221;, your site traffic drops. Your once bustling online store is quieter than a ghost town. Potential customers have suddenly disappeared and you’re left with an online store with no &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Traffic was never an issue for you until one day &#8220;BAM!&#8221;, your site traffic drops. Your once bustling online store is quieter than a ghost town. Potential customers have suddenly disappeared and you’re left with an online store with no customers. Where did your traffic go? How do you get your customers back? Today we’re sharing 7 strategies to implement when your website traffic drops.</p>
<p>If you already use <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/" target="_blank">Google Analytics</a>, you have access to demographics of your visitors. If you do not already have Google Analytics, set it up today. It provides statistics like percentage of returning vs new visitors, bounce rate and referrals source which will help you decide which strategies to implement.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17365" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/en-7strategies-1.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17332"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">1) Improve Your SEO</span></h2>
<p>If majority of your traffic originated from organic searches, Google’s new search algorithm may be penalizing your site for making one or more of these <a href="http://boostblogtraffic.com/seo-mistakes/" target="_blank">SEO mistakes</a>. After addressing one … or many of these issues, <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35843" target="_blank">submit a reconsideration request</a>. You can also submit your updated URL to other site engines like <a href="http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url" target="_blank">Bing </a>and <a href="http://www.dmoz.org/docs/en/add.html" target="_blank">Dmoz </a>to increase traffic. Prepare for Google to re-index your site by updating your Meta descriptions. They should not only describe your online store but be enticing enough to draw customers in. Next, generate a new site map, which outlines the layout of your website (from the PrestaShop Back Office, Google Sitemap Module, Configure, Generate Sitemap.)</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">2) Drive Traffic with Social Media</span></h2>
<p>Your online store should have at least one social media account, preferably the one your target customers engage with the most. Not sure which is best? Check out these <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2013/02/14/the-demographics-of-social-media-users-2012/" target="_blank">demographics of social media users</a> put together by PewResearch. After setting up an account, your first order of business it to complete your profile. Your profile should include an appropriate and relevant profile picture as well as a link back to your store. Check out <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">PrestaShop’s Twitter Account</a> for an example! Be sure to contribute relevant information on a regular basis and occasionally promote your products.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17333" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/PS-Twitter.png" alt="" width="207" height="371" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">3) Leverage Content Marketing</span></h2>
<p>Have you set up a blog for your online store? Get started by reading our previous blog post about <a title="Content Marketing for Ecommerce: Technical checklist and Writing process" href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/content-marketing-for-ecommerce-technical-checklist-writing-process/" target="_blank">content marketing for ecommerce</a>. The important takeaway? Content marketing is a strategy that takes time and dedication. To successfully run and maintain a blog, you must write good and relevant content. Here’s a look at how content marketing drives traffic:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17334" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/SEO.png" alt="" width="504" height="225" /></p>
<p>Already using content marketing? Here are 3 tasks to take on today.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/authorship" target="_blank">Set up Google+ Authorship</a> (to have an author image appear next to your article)</li>
<li>Incorporate color, images and headers tags (such as &lt;h1&gt; )</li>
<li>Use relevant keywords
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Here’s sample text for an online store selling pens:
<ol>
<li><strong>Bad</strong>: I enjoy selling products online<em> *no keywords used</em></li>
<li><strong>Very Bad</strong>: I enjoy selling pen, pens, cheap pens, blue pens, and personalized pens online.<em> *keyword stuffing</em></li>
<li><strong>Good</strong>: I enjoy selling pens online <em>*specifying with relevant keywords</em></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">4) Reach Out to Customers</span></h2>
<p>Email customers to get feedback about your site and suggestions for improvements. Try questions like:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>“What are your first impressions of our website?”</li>
<li>“On a scale from 1-10, how would you rate your experience?”</li>
<li>“How can we improve our online store?&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>For more examples check out <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/customer-satisfaction-surveys/?ut_source=header" target="_blank">SurveyMonkey’s Customer Satisfaction Surveys</a>. Respect your customer’s time by keeping response times to 5 minutes. Focus your attention on Problems and issues that are often repeated. Also, give customers an incentive to provide feedback by offering an online gift certificate. By doing so, you also drive traffic to your online store.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">5) Share Your Knowledge</span></h2>
<p>What are you a self-proclaimed expert at? What need does your online store fulfill? Think of questions potential customers may ask. Then find those customers on forums and answer their questions and suggest an appropriate product.</p>
<h4>An example for online stores:</h4>
<p><strong>Retailer: </strong>PrestaShop Jewelry Store (<a href="www.harryfay.co.uk" target="_blank">Harry Fay</a>)<br />
<strong>Sample Question:</strong> What to get my <a href="https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20130703131455AA6ewIz" target="_blank">girlfriend for her birthday</a>?<br />
<strong>Sample Answer: </strong><br />
“Necklaces are a good choice as they&#8217;re easier for guys to choose.<br />
If she already wears necklace, get a similar one.<br />
Here are two completely different ones that I quickly found.<br />
<a href="http://www.harryfay.co.uk/necklaces-and-pendants/88-owl-baltic-amber-silver-pendant.html" target="_blank"> Owl Necklace</a><br />
<a href="http://www.harryfay.co.uk/necklaces-and-pendants/46-silver-heart-pendant-with-17-cubic-zirconias.html" target="_blank"> Heart Necklace</a><br />
Good luck. I know how difficult it is to find presents.”</p>
<h4>Also, check out how our Community Manager promoted PrestaShop for the best ecommerce solution on <a href="http://www.quora.com/Which-ecommerce-solution-is-better-for-Small-Business-owners-Volusion-Shopify-Prestashop-BigCommerce" target="_blank">Quora</a>:</h4>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17369" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/ecommerce-solution.png" alt="" width="478" height="507" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">6) Start a PPC (Pay Per Click) Advertising Campaign</span></h2>
<p>Run an online advertising campaign on search engine affiliated <a href="http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/2728-25-Advertising-Networks-for-Online-Businesses" target="_blank">advertising networks</a> like Google AdWords and Yahoo Bing Ads. Both platforms offer similar functionalities like daily max budgets, Geo location targeting and campaign analytics. Start by determining the budget for your advertising campaign. Next, create a list of keywords or terms that potential customers might search. Finally, write the copy for your ads and start your campaigns. Keep in mind that these two factors drive up the cost of your ads 1) non relevant keywords and 2) the popularity of a keyword.</p>
<p>Aside from PPC Ads, there are many other ways to advertise online. Some examples include <a href="https://www.facebook.com/advertising" target="_blank">Facebook Ads</a>, <a href="http://business.pinterest.com/en/content/webform/promoted-pins" target="_blank">Promoted Pins</a>, and even through affiliate marketing on <a href="http://www.shareasale.com/" target="_blank">ShareASale</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">7) Upgrade Your Online Store</span></h2>
<p>Invest in your online store to improve visitors’ user experience. Where exactly should you invest your time? Start by analyzing your site with <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/" target="_blank">Google’s Page Speed Insights</a>. The results give you a report with problem areas segmented by a mobile and desktop views. Address mobile/ responsive issues by upgrading to PrestaShop 1.6. If you’re not sure how to make those changes, consider hiring a <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners" target="_blank">PrestaShop certified web developer</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17337" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/GoogleSiteSpeed.png" alt="" width="508" height="303" /></p>
<p>Other upgrades to consider include:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Upgrading hosting to increase site speed</li>
<li>Increasing your advertising budget</li>
<li>Purchasing mistyped URLs (Such as <a href="http://www.prestashop.net" target="_blank">www.PrestaShop.net</a> for <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">www.PrestaShop.com</a>)</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>Are you experiencing a drop in your site traffic? Which of these strategies will you consider implementing? Try it out and let us know how it works!</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="33%" />
</div>
<p>Not an online merchant yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">Demo PrestaShop</a>, the best ecommerce software, to get a feel for our software or <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">download </a>PrestaShop and start selling online today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce: must-have payment methods in Europe</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Exciting times lie ahead: your ecommerce business is growing and you’re finally in a position to begin exploring opportunities across the border. So, how do you prepare your ecommerce business for cross-border selling? Which key elements should you consider and &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting times lie ahead: your ecommerce business is growing and you’re finally in a position to begin exploring opportunities across the border.</p>
<p>So, how do you prepare your ecommerce business for cross-border selling? Which key elements should you consider and implement on your website straightaway?<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17319" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/handsglobere.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="277" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17309"></span>When it comes to online shopping there are truly no borders. Digital communities of online buyers have sprung up, looking for the best deals around the world. Representing a great opportunity for online stores, especially as global ecommerce sales are set to grow, according to recent studies by <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/Global-B2C-Ecommerce-Sales-Hit-15-Trillion-This-Year-Driven-by-Growth-Emerging-Markets/1010575" target="_blank">eMarketer.com</a>.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17311 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Emarketer.167671_re.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="292" /></p>
<p>However, even though the internet has undoubtedly paved the way for globalization and international exposure, allowing businesses to reach a much wider audience, the phrase <strong>‘Think Global, Act Local’</strong> is more relevant today than ever before!</p>
<p><strong>Localization</strong><br />
Localization is a key aspect of cross-border selling and it should be carefully evaluated in order to convert foreign customers.</p>
<p>Three basic elements of localization should be considered:</p>
<p><strong>1- Translating your website into the language of the country you wish to target</strong><br />
New Research clearly shows that most shoppers are likely to buy a product if they can place the order in their native language, as stated by <a href="http://www.kwintessential.co.uk/read-our-blog/localization-important-for-successful-global-ecommerce.html" target="_blank">Kwintessential</a>.<br />
- 55% of the participants affirmed that they prefer to buy a product from websites providing information in their own language; this figure was as high as 80% for people who don’t speak English</p>
<p><strong>2- Displaying prices in the local currency</strong><br />
This will help buyers make a decision faster, as opposed to having to convert prices</p>
<p><strong>3- Offering local payment methods</strong><br />
This is key to convert customers. Providing the preferred local method of payment, will prevent you from losing sales to your competitors.</p>
<h2>What are the most relevant payment methods per country, in Europe?</h2>
<p>The choice of payment method varies from country to country and is strongly related to the availability of local financial services. The table below offers an overview of preferred payment options, based on a study conducted by <strong>InnoPay &#8211; “Online Payments 2012. Moving beyond the web”<strong>.</strong></strong></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17310 alignnone" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/HiPay-Countries.png" alt="" width="600" height="379" /></p>
<h2>HiPay Wallet: payment solutions specific to each country</h2>
<p>HiPay Wallet is the only solution, in Europe, that provides alternative payment solutions specific to each country, in addition to the classic bank card offer.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Xo5XG4JGyLPR1kq0fCdsbRkLUALIbgCsegXdc03eoaV5f2RV2dAY3rHrf6pw2x981BFH_6zzwbPwwOzEmj80788ZgjlBThuAqcU7taLC-cyEQQX-XPkg86oXzFANuxyK6w" alt="" width="195px;" height="113px;" /><br />
HiPay constantly works and negotiates with banks, to be able to offer all the payments solutions that are used across Europe.</p>
<p>You can now allow your customers to purchase more easily and pay with their preferred payment options: bank transfers, cash payments, pre-authorized bank withdrawals, debit and credit card.</p>
<p><strong>Below, an overview of some of the options available through HiPay Wallet</strong>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/pmSMlDH_l8TN-e4cKnfw8y-x51FKFyGkCFLCOBHvlv1_p4HYNosRgjGlHs5sk_qcCFAbaABIEVUgN6ZZTRreh9Npbm6sjIC2ydd28bNQN6muGCupimEjBeJVCV2-wwOBQA" alt="" width="426px;" height="332px;" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1746-hipay.html" target="_blank">HiPay’s module</a> is available for the following countries: <strong>France, Belgium, Switzerland, United Kingdom, Spain, Italy, Netherlands, Germany, Portugal, Norway, Poland, Romania and the Czech Republic</strong>. The module is native in the software – for versions 1.5 and 1.6. Alternatively, it can be downloaded for free on <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce Design: How to Find the Right Logo for Your Online Store</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 15:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Finding the right logo for your online store is one of the most important decisions you’ll make as an online merchant. As legendary Logo Designer Paul Rand says, “A logo is a flag, a signature… a street sign.” Your logo &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finding the right logo for your online store is one of the most important decisions you’ll make as an online merchant. As legendary Logo Designer <a href="http://www.lifeclever.com/paul-rand-thoughts-and-despair-on-logo-design/" target="_blank">Paul Rand</a> says, “A logo is a flag, a signature… a street sign.” Your logo should clearly define your business model for your target audience. With so many options and possibilities for logo designs, where should you start?</p>
<p>Today we’re sharing tips on how to find the right logo for your online store. We’ll start with 5 qualities to look for, then share examples of powerful logos from live PrestaShop Stores, and finish with valuable resources to help you find your perfect logo.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17241" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/EN_ECOMMERCE-DESIGN.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17240"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080;">5 Q</span><span style="color: #008080;">ualities You’ll Find in the Right Logo</span></h2>
<h4>1) Memorable and Unique</h4>
<p>our logo should visually convey features that set your company apart from the competition. It should also make a strong and lasting impression – something that customers can also easily recall. With that said, your logo should also be unique and not resemble another company’s logo too closely to avoid confusion.</p>
<h4>2) Appropriate</h4>
<p>Finding the appropriate logo is a 2 step process. First it should <strong>accurately describe your brand</strong>. Then ensure that message is conveyed to your <strong>target customer</strong>.</p>
<h4>3) Timeless</h4>
<p>Ensure your logo is timeless by not relying too heavily on trends. Not sure what design trends are? Think stylistic designs like gradients, transparent layers, and futuristic fonts that were popular a few years ago. See what they look with examples of 2008’s Design Trends from <a href="http://www.logoorange.com/logo-design-08.php" target="_blank">LogoOrange</a>.</p>
<h4>4) Properly Colored</h4>
<p>We naturally associate colors with ideas and feelings. Get the most out of your logo by using colors that represents your brand. According to <a href="https://99designs.com/launch/brand-identity-pack/7ac5d0fd8f00bb21/brief" target="_blank">99Designs</a>, some common association of color in Western Culture are:</p>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>Red</strong></span>: Passion, Anger, Vigor, Love, Danger<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #ff9900;"><strong>Orange:</strong></span> Creativity, Invigoration, Unique, Stimulation<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #e4c547;"><strong>Yellow:</strong></span> Knowledge, Energy, Joy, Intellect, Youth<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #339966;"><strong>Green:</strong></span> Fertility, Wealth, Healing, Success, Growth<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>Blue:</strong></span> Knowledge, Trust, Tranquility, Calm, Peace, Cool<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #993399;"><strong>Purple:</strong></span> Royalty, Wisdom, Spirituality, Imagination<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #ffffff; background-color: #000000;"><strong>White:</strong></span> Purity, Healing, Perfection, Clean, Virtue<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #999999;"><strong>Gray:</strong></span> Balance, Sophistication, Neutrality, Uncommitted<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Black:</strong></span>Fear, Secrecy, Formal, Luxury</p>
<p>Do not, however, rely solely on color for effect. Make sure your logo also works in black and white.</p>
<h4>5) Simple and Clear</h4>
<p>Logos are meant to be an easy way for customers to remember your company. Show your logo to a stranger for 10 seconds. Did they get a good idea of your brand and company from the logo? If not, simplify the design. Stick to no more than 2 types of unscripted fonts. Then, remove any unnecessary designs.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080;">Let’s Get Technical</span></h2>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Use vector images.</strong></span> These types of images are created with mathematical equations which allows them to be scaled small or large without pixelating. According to <a href="http://www.olypress.com/vector-vs-raster-graphics-in-printing/" target="_blank">Olympus Press</a>, “crisp edges” are the most important aspect of a logo. Vector images will ensure your logo keeps its crisp edges.</p>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Create logos in varying sizes.</strong></span> Your logo should be consistent across all areas of your online store. However, it may not always fit into the specified dimensions. Take for example the various default sizes for the different logos placements within PrestaShop. (Easily edit these from the Back Office &gt; Preferences &gt; Themes.)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>           <span style="color: #ffffff;"> </span>         o Header Logo (350px X 99px)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>       <span style="color: #ffffff;">    </span>          o Favicon (16px X 16px)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>           <span style="color: #ffffff;"> </span>         o Store Icon (30px X 30X)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff;">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Create versions for different print mediums</strong></span>. Letter heads, business cards, envelopes, as well as advertising posters are just a few other places you might use your logo. Make sure you have a version that works with each medium you use.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080;">Examples of Logos from PrestaShop Stores</span></h2>
<p>Check out these great logos! Can you guess what these PrestaShop merchants sell just from their logos?</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.starcowparis.com/10-shop" target="_blank"><strong>Starcow Paris </strong></a><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17243" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Starcow-Logo.jpg" alt="" width="162" height="90" /> <img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17244" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/StarcowImage2.jpg" alt="" width="247" height="151" /></h4>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> Premier Parisian retailer for streetwear with skate and hip-hop influence<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> For starters, their logo is timeless. They steered clear of graffiti influence or highly styled fonts. Although the S in the logo has lots of character, it is still easy to understand. Furthermore, the scripted font reflects the prices and feel of their store; it’s refined with a little bit of edge and style.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.yumise.com/american-gourmandises" target="_blank"><strong>Yumise</strong></a><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17247" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Yumise-Logo.jpg" alt="" width="293" height="168" /></h4>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> French retailer for edible American products<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> This font is relevant for food lovers yet easy to understand. They clarify their unique brand name with a clear tagline below the store name to summarize the business model. It is simple but clearly shows the brand image.</p>
<h4><strong><a href="http://printthemall.com/" target="_blank">Print Them All</a></strong></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17242" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/printthemall-logo.png" alt="" width="152" height="176" /><br />
<strong>Business Model:</strong> Art dealer for prints from street artist.<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong>The use of gray, which projects neutrality, is perfect for an art dealer. The understated logo clearly communicates their role in the art process – feature the artist. The modern use of the fountain pens also shows the rebellious side of the company. This works well to showcase how they differentiate themselves in an established business market.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.todobonito.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Todo Bonito</strong><br />
</a></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17245" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/todobonito1.png" alt="" width="144" height="144" /><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17246" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/todobonito2.png" alt="" width="394" height="68" /></p>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> Downloadable cutout designs for children parties and celebrations.<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> The doily pattern behind the text alludes to the products that company sells – paper with designs that can be cut out. They also have multiple logos for different size requirements. The square logo is perfect for social media profile images where the rectangular logo works well for ecommerce headers. Finally, the pink hues are perfect for their target audiences – moms planning kid parties.</p>
<p>Need more sample logos for inspiration? Check out <a href="http://www.logomoose.com/" target="_blank">LogoMoose </a>or <a href="http://www.logoorange.com/logo-design.php" target="_blank">LogoOrange</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080;">Resources for Logo Designs</span></h2>
<p>So now that you know what to look for in a logo, how do you find you own? For online stores with small budgets, <a href="http://www.fiverr.com/search/gigs?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;search_in=everywhere&amp;query=logo&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;jls_se99912_1_auto=1" target="_blank">Fiverr </a>is a good resource with almost 20,000 different graphic designers offering their services for just $5. For more substantial budgets, consider <a href="http://99designs.com/how-it-works" target="_blank">99 designs </a>for ready-made logos starting at $99 or start a logo design contest starting from $299.</p>
<p>Already have a logo for your online store &#8211; how did you find it? Share in the comments below!</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="33%" />
</div>
<p>Not an online store owner yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">Demo PrestaShop</a> – the best ecommerce software – or get started today by <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">downloading</a> this online shopping cart software for free!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Install PrestaShop : The Complete Guide</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-install-prestashop/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-install-prestashop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you are searching how to install PrestaShop, you came to the right place. With nearly 4 million downloads and over 185,000 active stores, installation tutorials are always a popular request. Thankfully, there are tons of resources online to help &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-install-prestashop/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you are searching how to install PrestaShop, you came to the right place. With nearly 4 million downloads and over 185,000 active stores, installation tutorials are always a popular request. Thankfully, there are tons of resources online to help you install PrestaShop any way you like. You can install via a one-click installation script provided by your hosting provider. You can install it manually via MySQL and FTP. Lastly, you can install a localhost version of PrestaShop on your personal device for testing or development purposes. I’ll provide simple instructions for each of these scenarios. Enough with the introduction, let’s start installing!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/prestashop-1.6-604x272-1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17286" title="prestashop-1.6-604x272-1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/prestashop-1.6-604x272-1.png" alt="" width="604" height="272" /></a><span id="more-17189"></span></p>
<p>Before we get started you should get familiar with the <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Installing+PrestaShop">Official Installation Documentation</a>. This should serve as the point of reference for the various methods we will describe.</p>
<h3><span style="font-size: 14px;"> </span><strong><span style="color: #552d36;">1. One Click Install:</span> </strong></h3>
<p><strong> </strong>If you guessed that this the easiest method to install PrestaShop, you would be right. The first step would be to have a web-hosting provider who has a one-click installation script for PrestaShop. Ask your hosting provider if they include a one-click install. There are three popular script libraries to install PrestaShop with one click.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.simplescripts.com/script_details/install:PrestaShop"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">SimpleScripts</span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://installatron.com/prestashop"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Installatron</span></a></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.softaculous.com/apps/ecommerce/PrestaShop">Softaculous</a></span></li>
</ol>
<p>All you need is the FTP information that your webhost provided you. Contact your host if you do not have your FTP credentials. Some hosts have their own installation scripts.</p>
<p>PrestaShop  has teamed up with the best hosting companies that provide you with the easiest method to get your online store up and running. <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-hosting">Check out our Hosting page for more details.</a>  These are the hosts that know PrestaShop, with servers that are optimized for ecommerce performance.</p>
<h3><span style="color: #552d36;"><strong>2. How to Install PrestaShop Manually:</strong></span></h3>
<p><strong> </strong>If you already have knowledge about MySQL databases and FTP, then this would be for you. We have provided an instructional video below.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/psz4aIPZZuk" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<p>Here is a list of quick steps to install for the experienced users. For <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Installing+PrestaShop#InstallingPrestaShop-Detailedinstructions">more detailed instructions, see here</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Download and unzip the PrestaShop package onto your computer.</li>
<li>Create a database for PrestaShop shop on your web server if it is possible. In case there is no MySQL user who has all privileges for accessing and modifying this database, create it as well.</li>
<li>Upload the PrestaShop files and folders to the chosen location on your web server. Do not upload the root /prestashop folder directly: only the files and folders that it contains.</li>
<li>Run the PrestaShop installation script by accessing the public URL for the chosen location in a web browser. This should be the URL where you uploaded the PrestaShop files.</li>
<li>Follow the instructions on each screen of the installer.</li>
<li>Once the installation is done, delete the /install folder and write down the new of the /admin folder, which has been generated in order to be unique to you, for security reasons.</li>
</ul>
<h3><span style="color: #552d36;"><strong>3. How to Install PrestaShop Locally</strong>:</span></h3>
<p>A local installation means that PrestaShop is not live on the internet for the world to see, but it is live on your local computer or server. Only you can access to the local install. Having a local installation of PrestaShop is a great idea. You can test changes, upgrades and modules on a local installation on your computer without touching your live store.<br />
There are various tools you can use to install PrestaShop locally.  <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Installing+PrestaShop+on+your+computer">Refer to this page</a> in the documentation for Local installations.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.wampserver.com/en/">WAMP</a> (Windows)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apachefriends.org/en/xampp.html">XAMPP</a> (Windows, Mac OSX, Linux, Solaris)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.easyphp.org/">MAMP</a> (Mac OS X)</li>
</ol>
<p>Probably more useful are the are two local installation packages that include an out-of-the-box installation of PrestaShop. These make it easier for people who are less technical to have a local installation.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.easyphp.org/prestashop.php">EasyPHP</a> (Windows) -</li>
<li><a href="https://bitnami.com/stack/prestashop">BitNami</a> (Windows, Mac OSX, Linux) &#8211; <a href="https://bitnami.com/stack/prestashop/README.txt">Installation Read Me</a></li>
</ol>
<h3><span style="color: #552d36;">Final Thoughts</span></h3>
<p>There you have it, now you know how to install PrestaShop virtually anywhere. If you have questions, the place to go would be our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/forum/7-installing-prestashop/">dedicated Forum for PrestaShop installation</a>. Your community managers and moderators are active and ready to help out. Most of the issues you will encounter with installation are Server-side issues, usually permissions. That’s why it’s best to go with a Hosting partner with PrestaShop. Installing PrestaShop is just the first step to turn your idea into a money making success online. Thanks for reading and be sure leave your comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-install-prestashop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: We’re hanging out in Peru with Wataweb!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-were-hanging-out-in-peru-with-wataweb/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-were-hanging-out-in-peru-with-wataweb/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 17:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ecommerce in Peru is unlike anything we&#8217;ve seen so far. This ecommerce market is not only in its early stages of development but is also fighting to change consumer behavior. We’ve met with Wataweb, a local web agency that builds &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-were-hanging-out-in-peru-with-wataweb/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ecommerce in Peru is unlike anything we&#8217;ve seen so far. This ecommerce market is not only in its early stages of development but is also fighting to change consumer behavior. We’ve met with <a href="http://www.wataweb.com/" target="_blank">Wataweb</a>, a local web agency that builds online stores with PrestaShop, to learn more about ecommerce in Peru.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17185" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/PSWT-Lima-Main.jpg" alt="" width="560" height="375" /><span id="more-17183"></span></p>
<p>So what makes Peru so unique?</p>
<p>First,<strong> consumer behavior isn&#8217;t aligned with ecommerce practices</strong>. Shoppers regularly use cash and those who have credit cards are reluctant to enter their information online. Besides, Peruvian consumers also believe they should pay only upon receipt of goods.</p>
<p>Second,<strong> local banks are reluctant to open accounts for ecommerce merchants</strong>. This hurts the growth of ecommerce by limiting the number of online merchants. However there is good news! PayPal is changing the standard by partnering with leading local banks to help open accounts for online merchants.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17184" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/PSWT-Lima2.jpg" alt="" width="560" height="377" /></p>
<p>Peru is taking big steps to expand their ecommerce market and we sat down with Javier, Daniel and Dionisio from Wataweb to better understand their views and expectations for ecommerce in Peru.</p>
<p>Watch the video!</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/95289493" frameborder="0" width="500" height="281"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/95289493">PrestaShop World Tour: We&#8217;re in Lima, Peru with Wataweb</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/prestashop">PrestaShop</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Next stop: <span style="color: #008000;"><strong>NORTH AMERICA!</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Want your city and PrestaShop store to be featured next? Or want to share important ecommerce facts about your country? Leave us a comment or give us a shout out using the hashtag #PSWorldTour on <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Twitter</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-were-hanging-out-in-peru-with-wataweb/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Free Tools for Every Ecommerce Professional</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-free-tools-for-every-ecommerce-professional/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-free-tools-for-every-ecommerce-professional/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether you’re an online store owner that’s just getting started or you’ve been running your store for years, you can always benefit from new online tools to enhance your online business. Here is a list of the top 10 free &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-free-tools-for-every-ecommerce-professional/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whether you’re an online store owner that’s just getting started or you’ve been running your store for years, you can always benefit from new online tools to enhance your online business.</p>
<p>Here is a list of the top 10 free tools for every ecommerce professional that will help with design creation, user testing, social media, SEO and the many tasks of being an online merchant. You’ll wonder how you lived without these free websites and apps before today!<br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17085" title="EN_10 Free Tools for Every Ecommerce Professional" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_10-Free-Tools-for-Every-Ecommerce-Professional.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="284" /><br />
<span id="more-17082"></span></p>
<h4>1. <a href="http://peek.usertesting.com/ " target="_blank">PEEK</a></h4>
<h5>Site testing</h5>
<p style="text-align: left;">PEEK is a new initiative by UserTesting that will give you unbiased insight on your websites usability from real users – completely for free. Submit your online store and you’ll receive a 5 minute video of a real person navigating your site. Peek will help you improve your online shop’s navigation and help you optimize the user experience to increase conversions and customer satisfaction.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17091" title="Peek" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Peek.jpg" alt="" width="610" height="310" /></p>
<h4>2. <a href="http://keepass.info/ " target="_blank">KeePass</a></h4>
<h5>Password management</h5>
<p>The life of an online store owner includes tons of passwords to remember. KeePass is an easy to use and secure password manager. Store all of your passwords in one database and lock it with a master key. Now you only need to remember one password! KeePass’ databases are encrypted using the most secure algorithms available and KeePass is Open source so you can see that the algorithms are correctly implemented.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17088" title="KeePass" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/KeePass.jpg" alt="" width="488" height="374" /></p>
<h4>3. <a href="http://evernote.com/skitch/ " target="_blank">Skitch</a></h4>
<h5>Smarter screenshots</h5>
<p>The perfect screen shot tool for communicating with your team, developers and designers. Skitch is an Evernote product that lets you take screen shots and add text and shapes so that you get your point across faster. Skitch also lets you save screen shots and share them as a link. You’ll find Skitch to be extremely useful when working with your developer and designer to create or update your site.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/2iHm37fYO6o?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<h4>4. <a href="https://bitly.com/ " target="_blank">Bitly</a></h4>
<h5>Tracked, shortened links</h5>
<p>Bitly lets you quickly create shortened links and track engagement in real time. This tool is especially great for online merchants sharing on social media. Bitly lets you save all of your links, view stats, add notes, add them to a bundle and see who else shared a Bitlink to your content. You can even track which social media networks the Bitlink was shared on, the times and dates it was clicked and where the clicks came from geographically.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-17083" title="bitly" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/bitly-1024x374.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="213" /></p>
<h4>5. <a href="http://www.responsinator.com/ " target="_blank">Responsinator</a></h4>
<h5>Mobile testing</h5>
<p style="text-align: left;">Responsinator lets you test your website across multiple devices. This is a great way to test your site’s responsive capabilities and see how mobile shoppers view your shop. You can view your site on different iPhone, Android, iPad and Kindle devices in portrait and landscape settings.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17090" title="Responsinator" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Responsinator.jpg" alt="" width="470" height="242" /></p>
<h4>6. <a href="http://moz.com/webinars " target="_blank">Mozinars</a> by Moz</h4>
<h5>Marketing webinars</h5>
<p style="text-align: left;">Though not a tool, Mozinars by Moz are extremely valuable webinars that teach you everything you need to know about online marketing. These free webinars usually run for about 45 minutes to an hour and a half and give you plenty of time to ask questions directly to the Moz team. Register for upcoming Mozinars or watch previous sessions to learn how to develop compelling content for your online business that help drive traffic, boost SEO efforts and increase your conversion rate.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17089" title="Moz" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Moz.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<h4>7. <a href="https://www.canva.com/ " target="_blank">Canva</a></h4>
<h5>Graphic design</h5>
<p>Canva is a website that makes it easier than ever to create beautiful graphic design. Easily create flyers, presentations, Facebook covers, blog graphics, invitations and more. With Canva’s easy search and drag capabilities, you’ll make designs just like a professional. This is a great tool to create custom designs for email campaigns, social media networks and landing pages.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/3FZGN7BCs6k?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<h4>8. <a href="https://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank">Hootsuite</a></h4>
<h5>Social media management</h5>
<p style="text-align: left;">Hootsuite lets you manage your social media accounts from one dashboard. You can schedule posts and track engagement with Hootsuite’s free plan. Schedule your online shop’s social media posts in advance and drive more traffic to your online store. Now, managing your social media networks can be a fast and efficient process.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17087" title="Hootsuite" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Hootsuite.jpg" alt="" width="574" height="182" /></p>
<h4>9. <a href="http://feedly.com/#discover " target="_blank">Feedly</a></h4>
<h5>Subscription feed</h5>
<p>Feedly places your favorite sites, blogs, Youtube channels and RSS feeds all in one place. Explore different topics or search your favorite websites and centralize all your news in one place. This is a great way to subscribe to your favorite ecommerce publications – including the PrestaShop blog – so that you never miss a beat.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class=" wp-image-17086 aligncenter" title="Feedly" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Feedly-1024x444.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="253" /></p>
<h4>10. <a href="http://www.portent.com/tools/title-maker/ " target="_blank">Portent’s Content Idea Generator</a></h4>
<h5>Content planning</h5>
<p>Having trouble figuring out what to blog about? Portent’s Content Idea Generator lets you simply enter the subject you want to write about then generates blog post titles for you. You may need to search a few times until you find one that works for you but it still beats hours of brainstorming and research.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17084" title="Content Idea Generator" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Content-Idea-Generator-1024x497.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="283" /></p>
<p>&#8212;-</p>
<p>As your business grows, you may want to upgrade to paid accounts but all of these sites and apps are free to get started today! Did you know that there are hundreds of free, ecommerce tools built-in to PrestaShop? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download PrestaShop</a> for free today or try the <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo</a> and see what you’re missing!</p>
<p>Did we miss something? Share your favorite online tools with the Community by commenting below or tweet to <a href="https://twitter.com/PrestaShop" target="_blank">@PrestaShop</a> on Twitter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-free-tools-for-every-ecommerce-professional/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ensuring safe payments with online bank transfers</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensuring-safe-payments-with-online-bank-transfers/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensuring-safe-payments-with-online-bank-transfers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 13:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17122</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Even the most experienced of online shoppers still wants to have a sense of security when paying for goods online, especially if they are not yet familiar with your online store. Building your visitors and potential buyers’ confidence is essential: &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensuring-safe-payments-with-online-bank-transfers/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even the most experienced of online shoppers still wants to have a sense of security when paying for goods online, especially if they are not yet familiar with your online store.</p>
<p>Building your visitors and potential buyers’ confidence is essential: your goal is to reduce your cart abandonment percentage and increase customer conversion, hence your sales. A survey carried out by eConsultancy shows that 58% of respondents abandoned their cart due to <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/11182-basket-abandonment-case-studies-and-tips-to-help-improve-your-conversion-rates#i.1yhza1nrqtd3qs" target="_blank">concerns about payment security</a>.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17172" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Image_Euros_UPC_Resizedaaaa.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="300" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17122"></span></p>
<h2>What are some simple ways to make buyers feel at ease shopping on your online store?</h2>
<p><strong>1</strong>. The most common security signs buyers will usually look for are a <strong>URL prefixed by ‘https’ and the little ‘padlock’ symbol</strong> next to it.</p>
<p>It goes without saying that even if your online store is secure, it’s important to show it! And visually implement all safety standards in order to make you customer feel safe.</p>
<p><strong>2</strong>. Making sure that your <strong>payment page is consistent with the overall look and feel of your store and brand identity</strong> is another way to reassure your customers that they are shopping on a safe site – on one and the same website.</p>
<p>More often than not, these pages are left unbranded, giving buyers the feeling that they are being redirected to another website.<br />
<strong>Applying some minimal branding</strong> to your payment page, e.g. your store logo or brand colours can help you convert more customers.</p>
<p><strong>3</strong>. However, shoppers will first check which payment methods are available on your online store and if they are trusted options, before proceeding with making a purchase.</p>
<h2>Secure payments through online bank transfers</h2>
<p>In Europe, online bank transfers are among the most popular online payment methods, for two main reasons:</p>
<p>- Most of the people have a bank account<br />
- Online bank transfers are usually offered by banks and government-approved companies</p>
<p>Let’s explore some of the advantages of online bank transfers and why this payment method ranks high among other payment options.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17171 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Image5_EN.png" alt="" width="350" height="219" /></p>
<p><strong>Advantages for the customers:</strong><br />
First and foremost, customers are familiar with the internet banking environment. They simply have to enter their <strong>banking details and use their PIN</strong> to execute the payment. A familiar environment increases the feeling of security.</p>
<p>In addition, with online bank transfers <strong>customers can pay rapidly</strong> and expect their orders to be processed faster, which mean their goods will be dispatched sooner.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, that fact that online bank transfers are usually offered by banks and authorized companies, it means that customers trust the system and feel safe using it.</p>
<p><strong>Advantages for e-merchants:</strong><br />
For merchants, online bank transfers represent a <strong>fast and cost-effective way to receive payments</strong>. Thanks to the quick, real-time payment confirmation, they can ship the goods immediately, increasing customer satisfaction.</p>
<p>Furthermore, online bank transfers offer <strong>protection against chargebacks</strong>, as payments cannot be so easily reversed.</p>
<p>Additionally, the overall <strong>handling costs tend to be lower</strong> than what the other payment methods offer.</p>
<h3>SOFORT – one of the leading direct payment providers in Europe.</h3>
<p>SOFORT Banking provides secure, online direct payments services to over 25,000 online stores in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>More than 12 million consumers</strong> have already made at least one payment with SOFORT Banking, benefiting primarily from:</p>
<p>- A convenient payment method, using familiar online banking details<br />
- High security thanks to a multi-level online banking authentication procedure and the use of unique confirmation codes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/LogoSOFORT_klarnagroupCompany_RGB°Resized.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-17168 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/LogoSOFORT_klarnagroupCompany_RGB°Resized.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="106" /></a></p>
<p><strong>SOFORT Banking</strong> is now available in eleven countries, including Germany. Online shoppers in Austria, Switzerland, the Netherlands, Belgium, Poland, Hungary, Italy, Spain, France and the UK can now use this payment method.</p>
<p><strong>PrestaShop e-merchants benefit from the following features:</strong></p>
<p>- Attractive conditions<br />
- Easy integration<br />
- No registration required for your customers<br />
- Real-time transaction confirmation</p>
<p>Take advantage of <a href="https://www.sofort.com/payment/users/register/prestashop_benefit" target="_blank">SOFORT’s exclusive special offer</a> for PrestaShop merchants: <strong>register until May 15th 2014</strong> to get one and half month for free &#8211; no monthly or transactions fees &#8211; and receive 50% off the installation fee, until June 30th 2014. <strong>The promotion is available to all new customers.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/9176-sofortbanking.html" target="_blank">SOFORT Banking’s module</a> is native in the PrestaShop software or it can be downloaded for free on <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace.</strong><br />
The module is compatible with v1.4.0.1 &#8211; v1.6.0.6.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensuring-safe-payments-with-online-bank-transfers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GitHub Tutorial Instructions for Beginners</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/github-tutorial-with-prestashop/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/github-tutorial-with-prestashop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 15:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Development Practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With 25,000+ commits from 175+ contributors in only 18 months, PrestaShop’s GitHub branches are an enormous success. Use this Github Tutorial to join in on the action. Staying true to our commitment of being Open-Source, our GitHub Repositories are becoming &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/github-tutorial-with-prestashop/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With 25,000+ commits from 175+ contributors in only 18 months, PrestaShop’s GitHub branches are an enormous success. Use this Github Tutorial to join in on the action. Staying true to our commitment of being Open-Source, our GitHub Repositories are becoming increasingly active each day as more community developers collaborate together. We welcome and encourage everyone to contribute to our Ecommerce solution using GitHub. You want in? Great.  I’ll briefly describe what GitHub is and provide step by step instructions on how you can contribute to the PrestaShop software using GitHub.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17072" title="Github Tutorial" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/THE-BEST-THINGAVAILABLE.png" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<h2><span id="more-17040"></span></h2>
<p>GitHub is fueled by the version control system Git, an Open-Source project built by <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/19/an-interview-with-millenium-technology-prize-finalist-linus-torvalds/">Linus Torvalds, creator of Linux</a>. GitHub allows easy collaboration for developers to contribute by allowing them to “fork” (copy) project files, make changes and submit the changes to the owner of the project. The owner of the project can then easily review the changes and accept or decline the changes. All of this is done with a user-friendly navigation on a web-based interface.</p>
<p>It provides a central hub for anyone around the world to modify and submit code to a project, while still allowing the owner easy management collaboration with their respective contributors. GitHub, sums it up nicely, “Git allows groups of people to work on the same documents (often code) at the same time, and without stepping on each other&#8217;s toes. It&#8217;s a distributed version control system.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>GitHub Tutorial: Contribute to PrestaShop in 10 Steps </strong></h2>
<p>PrestaShop 1.6 is written mostly in PHP. Other languages used throughout are JavaScript, HTML, CSS, the Smarty templating language, SQL, and XML.</p>
<p>Developers who want to contribute to PrestaShop’s Open-Source software can follow these steps. <strong>[Please note that these steps are only for contributing to the PrestaShop core 1.6 <span style="text-decoration: underline;">development</span> branch. Pull requests made to other branches may be ignored or deleted for code consistency.]</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>1)      Create your <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub account</a></h5>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17042" title="Github Tutorial" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Sign-Up.png" alt="Github Tutorial" width="598" height="107" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>2)      Find the <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop">PrestaShop Repository List</a></h5>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/2-Repository.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17043" title="Github Repository" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/2-Repository.png" alt="" width="595" height="197" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>3)    Choose the Repository  named “PrestaShop” this will be the latest version <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop">PrestaShop v1.6</a></h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Repository-Github.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17044" title="Repository Github" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Repository-Github.png" alt="" width="572" height="157" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>4)      Select the “1.6” branch from the dropdown seen below.<span style="color: #339966;"> <strong>[IMPORTANT: <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Do not</span> select branch named “master”, requests should only be made to the “1.6” branch.]</strong></span></h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/CHoose-Branch.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17045" title="CHoose Branch" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/CHoose-Branch.png" alt="" width="505" height="162" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>5)        Next, click on “Fork” to copy the project to your personal Github account.<span style="text-align: center;"> </span></h5>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/4-Fork.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17046" title="4) Fork" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/4-Fork.png" alt="" width="558" height="134" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>6)      Create another Branch within your Fork for your changes. I named mine “My-Changes”</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/5-Create-branch.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17047" title="5) Create branch" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/5-Create-branch.png" alt="" width="580" height="318" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>7)       Once you are in your newly created branch, example “My-Changes”, navigate to the specific file you want to modify and click Edit. Make sure that <span style="font-size: 14px;">your code changes follow our </span><a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Coding+Standards">Coding Standards</a></h5>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/6-Edit-File.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17048" title="6) Edit File" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/6-Edit-File.png" alt="" width="506" height="185" /></a><span style="font-size: 14px;">    </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>8)      Scroll to the bottom of the page and in Commit Summary, <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/How+to+write+a+commit+message">you <em>must </em>follow our notation rules</a> in order for your request to be committed.  Then click, “Commit Changes”</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/8-Commit-changes.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17049" title="8) Commit changes" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/8-Commit-changes.png" alt="" width="529" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>9)    <span style="color: #339966;">  <strong>[IMPORTANT] You must test your changes on your own local installation or test environment of PrestaShop to make sure the change is working as you expected.</strong> </span><br />
After you have tested and you are ready to move forward, you need to submit your Pull Request.  Navigate back to your Github branch, in my example it was named “My-Changes”,  and you will see a button to click that says “Compare &amp; pull request”</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/9-Compare-and-Pull.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17050" title="9) Compare and Pull" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/9-Compare-and-Pull.png" alt="" width="552" height="323" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>10)  Add additional comments and pictures before you send your request to our team. Make sure to <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop/blob/1.6/CONTRIBUTING.md">review the guidelines for contributing</a> and if everything is in order, click “Send Pull Request”</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/10-Send-pull-request.png" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17051" title="10) Send pull request" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/10-Send-pull-request.png" alt="" width="550" height="271" /></a></p>
<h5>That’s it! You did it. Now you’ll wait a bit for one of our core developers to either include your code changes to our software, comment on possible improvements to your code or state reasons why the code change will not be accepted.</h5>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Useful Links</span></strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>Read our <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Contributing+code+to+PrestaShop">Official Contribution Document</a></li>
<li>Got 15 minutes and want to learn Git? Check out these tutorials provided by GitHub: <a href="http://try.github.io/">http://try.github.io/</a></li>
<li>Stuck and need help? Visit GitHub’s Help page for common issues: <a href="https://help.github.com/">https://help.github.com/</a></li>
<li>All core files you commit in your pull request must respect/use the <a href="http://opensource.org/licenses/OSL-3.0">Open Software License (OSL 3.0)</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">More Ways to Contribute</span></strong></h4>
<p>If you are not a developer but still want to contribute to PrestaShop, don’t worry because there are other ways to help.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/">Join the PrestaShop Forum</a> and be active on one of the largest online retail communities in the world. With over 600,000 members and 30 languages/communities, you’ll be in the perfect place for Ecommerce discussions, tips, technical tutorials and more.</li>
<li><a href="https://crowdin.net/project/prestashop-official">Help translate PrestaShop in your language</a>. Thanks to contributions from our global Community, store owners can translate their online store in 60+ languages. Submit translations on PrestaShop&#8217;s CrowdIn page to help the Community sell all across the globe.</li>
<li>Found an issue or want to submit a feature request? <a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/">Use the Forge!</a> PrestaShop Forge is the official ticket-tracker for PrestaShop. You don’t need to be a developer to write a ticket or request an improvement. You will need to create an account on the Forge: <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/How+to+use+the+Forge+to+contribute+to+PrestaShop">follow these instructions</a> and then wait for a core developer to answer you.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">GitHub+PrestaShop = &lt;3</span></strong></h4>
<p>Join the movement and use GitHub and your developer skills to improve the PrestaShop solution.  We love Open-Source and are committed to providing the best Ecommerce experience available. Just remember one thing, we grow as you grow.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading and feel free to leave your comments or questions below.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/github-tutorial-with-prestashop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: What&#8217;s going on in Brazil!?</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-whats-going-on-in-brazil/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-whats-going-on-in-brazil/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 12:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here we are, in the most dynamic ecommerce market in South America: BRAZIL! Brazil is truly a country of entrepreneurs. They embrace the culture of building your own business and the popularity of online commerce makes it even easier for &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-whats-going-on-in-brazil/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here we are, in the most dynamic ecommerce market in South America: <span style="color: #333333;"><strong>BRAZIL!</strong></span></p>
<p>Brazil is truly a country of entrepreneurs. They embrace the culture of building your own business and the popularity of online commerce makes it even easier for Brasilians to succeed.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17112" title="Sao Paulo Brazil PrestaShop World Tour Header" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Sao-Paulo-Brazil-PrestaShop-World-Tour-Header.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="281" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17111"></span><br />
This country is also the 5th largest Internet market in the world and <em>represents about 60% of all B2C Ecommerce in Latin America</em>. Brazil is definitely a strong online retail market and international e-tailers should consider it as a key target to grow their South American customer base.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17113" title="Sao Paulo PrestaShop World Tour" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Sao-Paulo-PrestaShop-World-Tour.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="330" /></p>
<p>We met with Bruna from Agencia Web Shop in Sao Paulo, she’s an active member in the PrestaShop Community and the first PrestaShop freelancer/agency certified in Brazil.<br />
Watch the video interview to see what Agencia Web Shop has to share about ecommerce in Brazil!</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/93349189" frameborder="0" width="500" height="281"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/93349189">PrestaShop World Tour: Agencia Web Shop, Sao Paulo</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/prestashop">PrestaShop</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p><span style="color: #003366;">Next stop: <strong>LIMA, PERU!</strong></span></p>
<p>Want your city and PrestaShop store to be featured next? Or want to share important ecommerce facts about your country? Leave us a comment or give us a shout out using the hashtag <span style="color: #333333;"><strong>#PSWorldTour</strong></span> on <a href="https://twitter.com/PrestaShop" target="_blank">Twitter</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-whats-going-on-in-brazil/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Examples of Ecommerce Marketing Emails that Work!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 16:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16822</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Your customers’ inboxes are constantly flooded with marketing emails from retailers – so how can you make your communication stand out? Email marketing is becoming increasingly more important for ecommerce businesses in order to build customer loyalty, increase conversion rates &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your customers’ inboxes are constantly flooded with marketing emails from retailers – so how can you make your communication stand out? Email marketing is becoming increasingly more important for ecommerce businesses in order to <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-best-ways-to-build-customer-loyalty-for-your-online-store/ " target="_blank">build customer loyalty</a>, increase conversion rates and run a profitable online business.</p>
<p>Today, let’s dive deeper into the importance of this communication medium and check out examples of ecommerce marketing emails that work!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16824" title="EN_Ecommerce Marketing Emails" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_Ecommerce-Marketing-Emails.jpg" alt="" width="571" height="250" /><br />
<span id="more-16822"></span></p>
<p>By sending timely, relevant and most importantly engaging, conversion-oriented emails, you can successfully measure your shop’s marketing performance and ROI. It’s not easy to send a strong email campaign the first time – but it’s okay, you should always be testing what works for your customer base and what emails bring your business the most value.</p>
<p>Test different send times, different call to action buttons, different promotions, different templates until you finally understand what’s working. Take a look at Kiss Metric’s <a href="http://blog.kissmetrics.com/ab-testing-email-campaigns/ " target="_blank">Beginner’s Guide to A/B Testing: Email Campaigns that Convert</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Email marketing tips for online retailers:</span></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Develop a goal for every email campaign<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Write content that caters to your target customers<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Be timely and relevant – <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/important-shopping-dates-for-e-commerce-merchants-2014/#more-15626 " target="_blank">2014 Important Shopping Dates for Ecommerce </a><br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Include tracked links to measure conversions<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Use effective <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-importance-of-call-to-action-buttons-on-your-e-commerce-site/ " target="_blank">ecommerce call to action buttons</a><br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Keep it simple<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Don’t spam your subscriber base</p>
<p>The more you focus on the purpose of your email, the more likely you’ll get the open rate and click through rate you want to achieve.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #e46a5d;">What can email marketing do for your online business?</span></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Increase traffic and sales<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Promote products that are not selling<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Share new arrivals with customers<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Build a relationship with your customers<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Share news, promotions and relevant content</p>
<p>That’s not all! PracticalEcommerce went ahead and listed the <a href="http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/3875-Don-t-Forget-Email-Marketing-13-Reasons " target="_blank">13 reasons why email marketing is important for ecommerce merchants</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Ecommerce email template inspiration</span></h2>
<p>Let’s share different marketing emails from PrestaShop stores that are effective, engaging and successful. We’ve gone ahead and listed their email subject, the goal of the email and what we loved about each one. Each email template and design is unique to help inspire your next campaign!</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">American Vintage</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Email subject:</strong></span> “Top Drawer XXL Knits / Bestsellers”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="size-full wp-image-16831 aligncenter" title="American Vintage" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/American-Vintage.jpg" alt="" width="406" height="883" /></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Marketing objective:</strong></span> Drive traffic to a specific product page with hand selected items.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Why we love it:</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Use of large image and minimal text<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Strong call to action button<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Creative “1 Look A Day” page to help customers visualize products as outfits<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> 3 simple links at the footer</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Gretel Home</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Email subject:</strong></span> “Fresh Flowers”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16834" title="Gretel Home" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Gretel-Home.jpg" alt="" width="501" height="586" /></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Marketing objective:</strong></span> Introducing season-appropriate collection of products.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Why we love it:</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Timely and relevant for Spring<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Large, colorful, high quality image<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Only one main objective</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Bimba y Lola</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Email subject:</strong></span> “Online Exclusive”</p>
<p style="text-align: center; padding-left: 30px;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16832" title="Bimba y Lola" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Bimba-y-Lola.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="346" /></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: left;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Marketing objective:</strong></span> Announcing a collection exclusive for online shoppers.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: left;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Why we love it:</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Sharing exclusive info increasing customer loyalty<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Different angles of product</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Donna Wilson</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Email subject:</strong></span> “Mother’s Day [UK] is March 30th! Gifts for Mum at Donna Wilson”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16833" title="Donna Wilson" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Donna-Wilson.jpg" alt="" width="395" height="637" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Marketing objective:</strong></span> Drive customers to their Mother’s Day special product page</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Why we love it:</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Clean, matching colors<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Simple text, clear link<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Incentive with free gift<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Quick links at footer</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">What Goes Around Comes Around</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><span style="color: #000080;">Email subject:</span></strong> “Spring Fling: Shop our Latest Arrivals”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16836" title="What Goes Around NYC" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/What-Goes-Around-NYC.jpg" alt="" width="478" height="536" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong><span style="color: #000080;">Marketing objective:</span></strong> Spotlight on new arrivals</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong><span style="color: #000080;">Why we love it:</span></strong><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Use of seasonal phrases: Spring Fling<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> 1 link, 1 large image<br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Leverages the beginning of spring</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Todo Bonito</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Email subject:</strong></span> “New designs in our shop!”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16835" title="Todo Bonito" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Todo-Bonito.jpg" alt="" width="396" height="623" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Marketing objective:</strong></span> Attract customers to purchase new party design packages.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Why we love it:</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #000080;">•</span> Real life setups for images<br />
<span style="color: #000080;"><strong>•</strong></span> Colorful images with little text<br />
<span style="color: #000080;"><strong>•</strong></span> Barely noticeable watermark but great if subscribers share it</p>
<h2><span style="color: #e46a5d;">Ready to start your next ecommerce email campaign?</span></h2>
<p><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Step 1:</strong></span> Start collecting e-mails addresses – use opt-in buttons at checkout, integrate newsletter subscription buttons, promote your marketing emails via social networks and encourage customers to share it with their friends.</p>
<p><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Step 2:</strong></span> Select an email service provider. There’s hundreds out there but you want to find one that seamlessly integrates with your ecommerce software. PrestaShop has dozens of <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=email" target="_blank">email marketing modules on PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</a> that let you quickly and easily create beautiful emails for your customers.</p>
<p><span style="color: #000080;"><strong>Step 3:</strong> </span>Review the tips and email examples above and test what works best for your online business.<span style="color: #333333;"> Create an Excel file that<strong> tracks the following:</strong></span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Email subject line<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Send time<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Send date<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Number of subscribers<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Open rate<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Click through rate<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Unsubscribe clicks<br />
<span style="color: #e46a5d;">•</span> Content of email</p>
<p>This will help you once you’ve sent a few emails to look back and see what worked the best. Pay close attention to all the elements you’re tracking to start developing your own best practices.</p>
<p>&#8211;<br />
Start sending powerful email marketing campaigns that work with PrestaShop. Manage all of your communications directly from your back office, send personalized automatic emails for <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/search?search_query=abandoned+cart" target="_blank">abandoned carts</a> and run a profitable online business today</p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download PrestaShop</a> or test the <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo</a> and experience the world’s most powerful ecommerce solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Object Caching 827/981 objects using disk: basic

Served from: www.prestashop.com @ 2014-05-30 15:56:02 -->